trackingtime.co 2019-12-13

# Privacy Policy | Help Center

Current as of: May 25, 2018

Your privacy is important to us, and so is being transparent about how we collect, use, and share information about you. This policy is intended to help you understand:

This Privacy Policy covers the information we collect about you when you use our products or services, or otherwise interact with us (for example, by sending a support request), unless a diﬀerent policy is displayed. TrackingTime, we and us refers to Tracking Time LLC. We oﬀer a wide range of apps and tools as part of our service, including our web, mobile apps and chat bots. We refer to all of these products, together with our other services and websites as "Services" in this policy.  

If you hold a personal account with TrackingTime and the General Data Protection Regulation of the European Union is applicable to your use of the Services, TrackingTime is the Data Controller. TrackingTime’s address is: 1000 E HALLANDALE BEACH BLVD STE 28, Hallandale Beach, 33009 Florida and its telephone number is: +1 (585) 457-5087. You can also contact us at the following email address: [support@trackingtime.co.](mailto:support@trackingtime.co) If you hold an account managed by your employer or another organization, that organization is the Data Controller. Please contact us if you are uncertain who the Data Controller is with respect to your personal data. 

This policy also explains your choices about how we use information about you. Your choices include how you can object to certain uses of information about you and how you can access and update certain information about you. **The provision of your personal data is necessary for us to provide the Services to you and we will not provide the Services without it.** **If you do not agree with this policy, do not access or use our Services or interact with any other aspect of our business. The exercise of some of your rights listed in the section titled “Your Choices” may require us to cease providing the Services.  **

Where we provide the Services under contract with an organization (for example your employer) that organization controls the information processed in connection with the Services. For more information, please see _Notice to End Users_ below.

We collect information about you when you provide it to us, when you use our Services, and when other sources provide it to us, as further described below.

**Account and profile data** : We collect information about you when you register for an account, create or modify your profile, set preferences, sign-up for or make purchases through the Services. For example, you provide your contact information and, in some cases, billing information when you register for the Services. You also have the option of adding a profile photo and other details to your profile information to be displayed in our Services. We keep track of your preferences when you select settings within the Services.

**Services:** We keep track of your preferences when you select settings within the Services. 

**Data you provide through our products** : The Services include the TrackingTime apps you use, where we collect and store content that you post, send, receive and share. This content includes any information about you that you may choose to include. Examples of content we collect and store include: the name of your tasks, projects, customers or services you oﬀer and the work times associated to those entities and to you.

**Data you provide through our websites** : The Services also include websites owned or operated by us like trackingtime.co. We collect other content that you submit to these websites and data related to your use of social media in connection with the Services, for example, when you “like” or “share” something displayed through the Services using a widget provided by Facebook. You provide content to us when you provide feedback or when you participate in any interactive features (such as the ability to post comments), surveys, promotions or activities.

**Data you provide through our support channels** : The Services also include our customer support, where you may choose to submit information regarding a problem you are experiencing with the Services. Whether you designate yourself as a technical contact, open a support ticket, speak to one of our support representatives directly or otherwise engage with our support team, you will be asked to provide contact information, a summary of the problem you are experiencing, and any other documentation and screenshots or information that would be helpful in resolving the issue. In some cases, it might be helpful for us to access your account. In such cases, we’ll ask you for your permission beforehand.

**Payment data** : We collect certain payment and billing information when you register for paid Services. For example, we ask you to designate a billing representative, including name and email address, upon subscribing to a paid plan. We use this information for sending you invoices and payment receipts. However, **we never collect or store your credit card details.** Your credit card details such as card number, expiration date or security code are securely processed by Stripe Inc., our payments provider. To learn more about compliance and security of your payment data please visit Stripe’s website.

We collect information about you when you use our Services, including browsing our websites and taking certain actions within the Services.

**Your use of the Services** : We use third-party services to keep track of certain information about you when you visit and interact with any of our Services. The third parties that provide these services are listed at the end of this document. This information includes, for example, the features you use; the links you click on; the dates when you log into your account; and how you interact with the Services.

**Device and Connection Information** : We collect information about your computer, phone, tablet, or other devices you use to access the Services. This device information includes your connection type and settings when you install, access, update, or use our Services. We also collect information through your device about your operating system, browser type, IP address, URLs of referring/exit pages, device identifiers, and crash data. We use your IP address and/or country preference in order to approximate your location to provide you with a better Service experience. How much of this information we collect depends on the type and settings of the device you use to access the Services.

**Cookies and Other Tracking Technologies** : TrackingTime and our third-party providers, such as our analytics vendors, use cookies and other tracking technologies (e.g., web beacons, device identifiers and pixels) to provide analysis, functionality and to recognize you across diﬀerent Services and devices. These third-party providers are listed at the end of this document. Please refer to their privacy policies for more information regarding the use of cookies and other tracking technologies they use.

We receive information about you from other users of the Services and from third-party services. We may combine this information with information you give to us and information we collect about you.

**Other users of the Services** : Other users of our Services, including your employer, may provide information about you when they submit data through the Services. For example, you may be assigned a task by someone else that might include personal information related to you or to your work. We may also receive your email address from other Service users or your employer when they provide it in order to invite you to the Services. Similarly, an administrator may provide your contact information when they designate you as the billing contact on your company's account.

**Other services you link to your account** : We receive information about you when you or your administrator integrate or link a third-party service with our Services. For example, if you create an account or log into the Services using your Google credentials, we receive your name and email address as permitted by your Google profile settings in order to authenticate you. You or your administrator may also integrate our Services with other services you use. For example, you may use the TrackingTime Button for Chrome to track time within various third-party services. In this case, we automatically collect data from the integrated service such as task and project names.

Below are the specific purposes for which we use the information we collect about you.

**To provide the Services and customize your experience** : We use information about you to provide the Services to you, including to process transactions with you, authenticate you when you log in, provide customer support, and operate and maintain the Services.

For example, we use the name and profile picture you provide in your account to identify you to other Service users within your organization.

**For research and development** : We are always trying to make our Services better, faster, more secure, and more useful to our customers. We use collective learnings about how people use our Services and feedback provided directly to us to troubleshoot and to identify trends, usage, activity patterns and areas for improvement of the Services. For example, when we launch a new feature we track how often it’s used and by whom.

**To communicate with you about the Services** : We use your contact information to send transactional communications via email and within the Services, including confirming your payments, reminding you of subscription expirations, responding to your comments, questions and requests, providing customer support, and sending you technical notices, updates, security alerts, and administrative messages. We send you email and in-app notifications when you or others interact with you on the Services, for example, when a task is assigned to you. We also provide tailored communications based on your activity and interactions with us. For example, certain actions you take in the Services may automatically trigger an email or in-app message. We also send you messages as you onboard your team to help you become more proficient in using our products. These communications are part of the Services and you can always unsubscribe from them. Also, you can always change your notification settings according to your preferences to avoid receiving certain types of notifications. To learn more about how you can customize your notification preferences and how to unsubscribe [please refer to this article](http://support.trackingtime.co/user-guide/web-app-overview/notifications).

**To market, promote and drive engagement with the Services** : We use your contact information and information about how you use the Services to send promotional communications that may be of specific interest to you, including by email. These communications are aimed at driving engagement, including selling the Services to you, and maximizing what you get out of the Services, including information about new features, survey requests and newsletters we think may be of interest to you. We also communicate with you about new product oﬀers, updates and promotions.

**Customer support** : We use your information to resolve technical issues you encounter, to respond to your requests for assistance, to analyze crash information, and to repair and improve the Services.

**For safety and security** : We use information about you and your Service use to verify accounts and activity, to monitor suspicious or fraudulent activity and to identify violations of Service policies.

**To protect our legitimate business interests and legal rights** : Where required by law or where we believe it is necessary to protect our legal rights, interests and the interests of others, we may use information about you in connection with legal claims, compliance, regulatory, and audit functions.

**With your consent** : We use information about you where you have given us consent to do so for a specific purpose not listed above. For example, we may publish testimonials or featured customer stories to promote the Services, with your permission.

If you are an individual in the European Economic Area (EEA), we collect and process information about you only where we have legal bases for doing so under applicable EU laws. The legal bases depend on the Services you use and how you use them. This means we collect and use your information only where:

We need it to provide you the Services, including to operate the Services, provide customer support and personalized features and to protect the safety and security of the Services;

It satisfies a legitimate interest (which is not overridden by your data protection interests), such as for research and development, to market and promote the Services and to protect our legal rights and interests; We need to do so to satisfy the terms of our agreement with you; You give us consent to do so for a specific purpose; or We need to process your data to comply with a legal obligation.

If you have consented to our use of information about you for a specific purpose, you have the right to change your mind at any time, but this will not aﬀect any processing that has already taken place. Where we are using your information because we or a third party (e.g. your employer) have a legitimate interest to do so, you have the right to object to that use though, in some cases, this may mean no longer using the Services.

We make productivity tools, and we want them to work well for you. This means sharing information through the Services and with certain third parties. We share information we collect about you in the ways discussed below, but **we do not sell information about you to advertisers or other third parties.**

When you use the Services, we share certain information about you with other Service users within your team or organization.

**For collaboration** : You can create content such as tasks, to-dos and comments, which may contain information about you, and grant permission to others to see, edit and copy that content. Some of the collaboration features of the Services display some or all of your profile information to other Service users when you share or interact with specific content. For example, when you comment on a task, we display your profile picture and name next to your comments so that other users with access to the task understand who made the comment. Please note that any data posted in the Services, including information about you, your business or your employees, cannot be publicly viewed and is only available to active users in your organization’s account who have been previously granted access by an account administrator.

**Managed accounts and administrators** : If you register or access the Services using an organizational account that is held by your employer or another organization or using an email address with a domain that is owned by your employer or another organization, and such organization wishes to establish an account or site, certain information about you including your name, profile picture, contact info, content and past use of your account may become accessible to that organization’s administrator and other Service users sharing the same TrackingTime account.

We share information with third parties that help us operate, provide, improve, integrate, customize, support and market our Services.

**Service Providers** : We work with third-party service providers to provide website and application development, hosting, maintenance, backup, storage, virtual infrastructure, payment processing, analysis and other services for us, which may require them to process, access or use information about you. These service providers are listed at the end of this document. Some of these service providers use “cookies” or other tracking devices on our site, which are software programs or other systems that collect information about your use of our Services. If a service provider needs to access information about you to perform services on our behalf, they do so under close instruction from us, including policies and procedures designed to protect your information.

**Third Party Apps** : You, your administrator or other Service users may choose to add new functionality by integrating third party apps within the Services. Doing so may give third- party apps access to your account and information about you like your name and email address, and any content you choose to use in connection with those apps. For example, if you or your account administrator use Zapier to integrate TrackingTime to other online services, your account data will be shared with the services you choose.

**Links to Third Party Sites** : The Services may include links that direct you to other websites or services whose privacy practices may diﬀer from ours. If you submit information to any of those third-party sites, your information is governed by their privacy policies, not this one. We encourage you to carefully read the privacy policy of any website you visit.

**Third-Party Widgets** : Some of our apps and websites may contain widgets and social media features, such as the Twitter "tweet" button. These widgets and features collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on the Services, and may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. Widgets and social media features are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Services. Your interactions with these features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it. If you do not know which company provides a particular widget please contact us so we can provide you with the information you require.

**With your consent** : We share information about you with third parties when you give us consent to do so. For example, we often display personal testimonials of satisfied customers on our public websites. With your consent, we may post your name alongside the testimonial.

**International Transfers** : TrackingTime is based outside of the EEA and so are many of our third-party service providers so processing of your personal data will involve a transfer of your personal data outside the EEA. The location where our third-party service providers process your personal data is shown at the end of this document. 

Whenever we transfer your personal data to a third-party outside of the EEA, we ensure a similar degree of protection is afforded to it by ensuring at least one of the following safeguards is implemented:

  * We will transfer your personal data to countries that have been deemed to provide an adequate level of protection for personal data by the European Commission; or
  * Where we use providers based in the US, we may transfer data to them if they are part of the Privacy Shield which requires them to provide similar protection to personal data shared between Europe and the US; or
  * Where we transfer your personal data to a country that the European Commission has not determined provides an adequate level of protection for your personal data and the relevant third party is not a part of the Privacy Shield (if the transfer is to the US), we may use specific contractual clauses approved by the European Commission which give personal data the same protection it has in Europe.

Please contact us if you want further information on the specific mechanism used by us when transferring your personal data out of the EEA.

**Corporate Transactions** : If TrackingTime or substantially all of its assets are acquired by a third party, personal data held by TrackingTime about its customers will be one of the transferred assets.

#### Information storage and security

We use data hosting service providers in the United States, listed at the end of this document, to host the information we collect, and we use technical measures to secure your data. For more information on where we store your information, [please see our Security & Trust page](http://support.trackingtime.co/plans-and-pricing/faq/security-and-trust) _._

While we implement safeguards designed to protect your information, no security system is impenetrable and due to the inherent nature of the Internet, we cannot guarantee that data, during transmission through the Internet or while stored on our systems or otherwise in our care, is absolutely safe from intrusion by others.

#### How long we keep information

How long we keep information we collect about you depends on the type of information, as described in further detail below. After such time, we will either delete or anonymize your information or, if this is not possible (for example, because the information has been stored in backup archives), then we will securely store your information and isolate it from any further use until deletion is possible.

#### Account information

We retain your account information for as long as your account is active and 9 months thereafter in case you decide to re-activate the Services. Where we retain information for Service improvement and development we only use the information to uncover collective insights about the use of our Services, not to specifically analyze personal characteristics about you.

#### Information you share on the Service

If your account is deactivated or disabled, some of your information and the content you have provided will remain in order to allow your team members or other users to make full use of the Services. For example, we continue to display messages you sent to the users that received them and continue to display content you provided.

#### Managed accounts

If the Services are made available to you through an organization (e.g., your employer), we retain your information as long as required by the administrator of your account. For more information, _see "Managed accounts and administrators" above_.

#### Marketing information

If you have elected to receive marketing emails from us, we retain information about your marketing preferences for a reasonable period of time from the date you last expressed interest in our Services, such as when you last opened an email from us or ceased using your TrackingTime account. We retain information derived from cookies and other tracking technologies for a reasonable period of time from the date such information was created.

You have certain choices available to you when it comes to your information. Below is a summary of those choices, how to exercise them and some limitations.

#### Your Choices:

You have the right to request a copy of your information, to object to our use of your information (including for marketing purposes), to request the deletion or restriction of your information, or to request your information in a structured, electronic format, the right to have your personal data rectified if it is incorrect, the right to withdraw your consent to processing of your personal data (where the consent is the lawful basis for such processing) and, if the General Data Protection Regulation of the European Union applies, the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority, which may be the Data Protection Authority in the country where you reside. 

Below, we describe the tools and processes for making these requests. You can exercise some of the choices by logging into the Services and using settings available within the Services or your account. Where the Services are administered for you by an administrator ( _see "Notice to End Users" below_ ), you may need to contact your administrator to assist with your requests first and we may not be able to give effect to your request if the administrator refuses it. For all other requests, you may contact us as provided in the Contact Us section below to request assistance.

#### Access and update your information

Our Services and related documentation give you the ability to access and update certain information about you from within the Service. For example, you can access your profile information from your account and search for tasks containing information about you using key word searches in the Service. You can update your profile information within your profile settings and modify your preferences and notification settings.

#### Cancel your account

If you no longer wish to use our Services, you or your administrator may be able to deactivate your Services account. If you can cancel your own account, i.e. you’re set up as account administrator, that option is available to you in your account settings. Otherwise, please contact your administrator. If you are an administrator and are unable to deactivate an account through your administrator settings, please contact TrackingTime support. Please be aware that deactivating your user account does not delete your information; your information such as tasks, time entries associated to you and task comments remains visible to other Service users based on your past participation within the Services. For more information on how to delete your information, see below.

#### Request to permanently delete your account data

In some cases, you may ask us to stop accessing, storing, using and otherwise processing your information. For example, if you believe a Services account was created for you without your permission or you are no longer an active user, you can request that we delete your account as provided in this policy. Where you gave us consent to use your information for a limited purpose, you can contact us to withdraw that consent, but this will not aﬀect any processing that has already taken place at the time. You can also opt-out of our use of your information for marketing purposes by contacting us, as provided below. When you make such requests, we may need time to investigate and facilitate your request. If there is delay or dispute as to whether we have the right to continue using your information, we will restrict any further use of your information until the request is honored or the dispute is resolved, provided your administrator does not object (where applicable).

#### Automatic account deletion

In response to the General Data Protection of the European Union we’ll automatically delete your account and all data associated to it from our production database if the account has been inactive for 9 months. An account is considered inactive when no users have logged into the account during a 9-month period. If a user returns after 9 months they will be treated like a new user and will need to signup for a new account. There will be no record of previous user data.

#### Opt out of communications

You may opt out of receiving promotional communications and automated transactional messages from us by using the unsubscribe link within each email, updating your notification preferences within your Service account settings, or by contacting us to have your contact information removed from all promotional and transactional emails. However, even after you opt out from receiving promotional messages from us, you will continue to receive certain transactional messages from us regarding our Services such as payment failure notices or account suspension notices sent via email. To learn more about the available notification settings and how to customize them to your preferences [please refer to this article](http://support.trackingtime.co/user-guide/web-app-overview/notifications).

**Export your account data (Data portability)** : Data portability is the ability to obtain some of your information in a format you can move from our Services to another. Should you request it, we will provide you with appropriate files containing all your account data (such as projects, clients, time entries, users, etc.) within 30 days upon receiving your request.

Additionally, you can always export your reports in CSV format for backup purposes or to import them into other software applications you use. If your account is managed by an administrator, we may require the administrator’s consent before we are able to give effect to a data portability request. 

Many of our products are intended for use by organizations. Where the Services are made available to you through an organization (e.g. your employer), that organization is the administrator of the Services and is responsible for the accounts and/or Service sites over which it has control. If this is the case, please direct your data privacy questions to your administrator, as your use of the Services is subject to that organization's policies. We are not responsible for the privacy or security practices of an administrator's organization, which may be diﬀerent than this policy.

If you do not want an administrator to be able to assert control over your account or use of the Services, use your personal email address to register for or access the Services. If an administrator has not already asserted control over your account or access to the Services, you can update the email address associated with your account through your account settings in your profile. Once an administrator asserts control over your account or use of the Services, you will no longer be able to change the email address associated with your account without administrator approval.

Current as of: May 25, 2018

To support the delivery of the Services, we use diﬀerent service providers that may store and process personal data about you and users you manage within your TrackingTime account. This section provides important information about the identity, location, and role of these Data Processors/Subprocessors. We use diﬀerent types of Processors/Subprocessors to perform various functions as explained in the table below.

  * **Mixpanel** (Product Analytics, United States)
  * **Google Analytics** (Product Analytics, United States)
  * **Amazon Web Services** (Cloud Infrastructure, United States)
  * **Nubity** (DevOps, United States)
  * **CloudFlare** (Content Delivery Network, United States)
  * **MailChimp** (Email messaging, United States)
  * **Baremetrics** (Business Analytics, United States)
  * **Intercom** (Customer Analytics, United States)

Any changes we may make to our privacy policy in the future will be posted on this page and, where appropriate, notified to you by e-mail. Please check back frequently to see any updates or changes to our privacy policy.

#### Contact Us

Tracking Time, LLC 

**Address:  **

1000 E HALLANDALE BEACH BLVD STE 28  
Hallandale Beach  
33009 Florida

**Phone** : +1 (585) 457-5087

**Email** : [support@trackingtime.co](mailto:support@trackingtime.co)
